Richard Walter

Sr. Technical Account Manager | richardwalter515@gmail.com | (336) 264-4558

CAREER SUMMARY

As a passionate and hardworking Technical Account Manager, I have experience managing difficult technical issues and collaborating across departments to advocate for my client. In my previous work as a Merchandise Manager, I gained strong leadership skills and learned to be creative, empathetic, and thoughtful about solving problems and providing an excellent customer experience while supporting my team however I could.

SELECT WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

React Portfolio https://richardwalter515.github.io/react-portfolio/
Utilized React JS to create a visually appealing and practical portfolio. Repository: https://github.com/richardwalter515/react-portfolio

GameKnight https://game-knight-app.herokuapp.com/

A full-stack game application I built to address a need my friends had during a game night. We've used this to help us roll dice and keep score. Repository: https://github.com/richardwalter515/game-knight

EXPERIENCE

Pendo.io, NC — Sr. Technical Account Manager

APRIL 2022 - PRESENT

- Leads team office hours weekly to help unblock fellow TAMs and offer best practices and guidance.
- Pioneered the Weekly Digest for high-touchpoint clients as a way to organize and communicate important information and track key initiatives.

Pendo.io, NC — Technical Success Engineer

MAY 2021 - APRIL 2022

- 100% Customer Satisfaction (CSAT) rating
- Salesforce Integration SME

Stiletto Entertainment, CA — *Merchandise Manager*

JUNE 2014 - JULY 2016

 Managed the merchandise team for the Barry Manilow One Last Time! Tour, completing 67 concerts across the US.

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina Chapel Hill —2020-2021 Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

New York University — 2017–2019 MFA in Musical Theatre Writina

• Class Vice President

UNC Chapel Hill — 2010-2014 BA in Communications, BA in Music

GitHub:

github.com/richardwalter515

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-walter-0bb141121/

SKILLS

An enthusiastic and empathetic leader with strong technical skills. Constantly curious and quick to learn new concepts, languages, and technologies. Eager to jump in when difficult situations arise and think creatively and strategically when navigating towards a solution. A strong writer with high proficiency in the Microsoft Office Suite of programs, Google products, VS Code, GitHub, Postman and working with REST APIs.

Additional Projects

Documentation Editor and Co-Founder - Helped spearhead a project to create new documentation focused on best-practices for using our tools, and served as documentation editor when the project went live.

Onboarding Lead - One of the leaders on the team responsible for improving and updating onboarding material as well as ensuring new hires are paired with a mentor and that onboarding is going smoothly.

LANGUAGES

React JS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, JQuery, mySQL, Handlebars, MongoDB, Python, JSON